# KARA EVANS

kara.e177409@gmail.com · <u>LinkedIn</u> · <u>Portfolio</u> Cleveland, Ohio | *Open to hybrid* & *remote roles*.

#### SUMMARY

Data analyst with more than nine years of experience with a focus in laboratory data analysis and application of problem-solving skills. Notable achievements include reducing departmental deviation reports by 20% within the first year of assignment and improving the laboratory inventory program resulting in cost savings and limited workflow disruptions for the organization. Adaptable and able to rapidly acquire new skills. Consistently takes on the role of training and educating fellow employees, contributing to team development and growth.

Skills: SQL, Tableau, Python, Statistical Analysis

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Optometric Technician, Dr. Jodi Rowson & Associates | January 2023-present

- Record patient data and schedule appointments using electronic health record system.
- Communicate with insurance companies to obtain patient eligibility information and initiate prior authorization requests.

## Senior Laboratory Technologist, Cleveland Cord Blood Center | November 2017-December 2022

- Evaluated risk of unexpected outcomes, conducted thorough investigations, and produced comprehensive investigative reports on a weekly basis. Consistently exceeded goal for report submissions by 400%.
- Maintained detailed inventory records with systematic tracking of supply counts, product information, and expiration dates to ensure optimal inventory control and regulatory compliance.

## Laboratory Technician, Cleveland Clinic | September 2015-November 2017

- Recorded patient data and monitored specimen tracking information using laboratory information management system.
- · Resolved issues related to patient samples ensuring timely resolution and effective communication to hospital staff.

## Analyst, CWM Environmental | August 2014-September 2015

Performed environmental analyses on industrial waste samples while adhering to client-specific deadlines.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Science, Biological Sciences, Certificate in Environmental Studies, Ohio University | May 2014

# **PROJECTS**

## **Staffing Allocation Plan**

Performed data cleansing and integration techniques on multiple data sets to support a staffing agency in its mission to strategically allocate medical staff throughout the United States during influenza seasons. Discovered trends using statistical analyses and visualizations created within Tableau. Developed a dynamic dashboard to illustrate areas most impacted by influenza infections.

### **Product Analysis**

Evaluated data from a movie rental company to provide insights ahead of the launch of a new video streaming service. Generated SQL queries and common table expressions to join data tables and answer complex business questions. Constructed visualizations in Tableau to convey findings such as geographical sales data, customer behavior, and film rental performance.

#### **Customer Analysis**

Conducted exploratory analyses on customer data derived from an online grocery store, aiming to understand customer demographics and behavior. Merged data frames, crafted new variables, and generated visualizations using Python. Findings include optimal advertising times and the identification of popular products.